Rensselaer County Greens; Records apap192
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Rensselaer County Greens Records
1979-2004
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap192
6.96 cubic ft.
The records of the Rensselaer County Greens (RCG) contain relevant information behind its efforts to protect the Rensselaer County, New York community from the destruction of environment and historical landmarks.
11 Videocassette Tapes
32 Audiocassette Tapes
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Eric Daillie of the Rensselaer County Greens donated this collection in February 2005.
Biographical History
The Rensselaer County Greens (RCG) was founded in January 1999. The organizations purpose is to strengthen the Rensselaer County community through the preservation of significant historical landmarks and through the encouragement of environmental-friendly procedures. The grassroots approach is designed to have the voice of every individual citizen interested in the community heard, with their involvement dictating how their community is run. No matter gender, race, age, or class, the RCG strives for the equal treatment for members of the Rensselaer community.
Since its inception, the organization has worked to save, protect, and dissuade Rensselaer County from accepting proposals that will compromise the environmental and living standards of the community. The RCG was a founding member of Historic Action Network. In RCGs first year of existence the organization successfully prevented a microchip semiconductor plant from being built in North Greenbush, NY. Behind one of the partys spokesmen, Eric Daillie, the Greens used community pressure to stop this microchip plant, known as Chip Fab, from being built. The environmental destruction and physical health issues that RCG believed would result led to their involvement in the issue.
In a more controversial and time-consuming case, the RCG spent the years 2000-2004 attempting to keep Besicorp out of Rensselaer. Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC, or BEDCO, wanted to build a $680 million state-of-the-art facility in Rensselaer in 2000. Besicorp planned to team up with Empire State Newsprint, LLC to create a recycled news clipping manufacturing facility and a cogeneration power facility. The desire to make the Hudson River waterfront aesthetically pleasing, protect the citizens from harmful pollutants, and to clean up the toxic by-products of the previous company, BASF, was the motivation for the RCG members to keep this new business out of Rensselaer. However, re-industrialization took precedence and both the power plant and the papermill received the necessary state permits to build. As of 2006, Besicorp has not constructed either facility.
The RCG has also been involved in many smaller projects during its existence. Preserving woodlands and farmland from being destroyed for the construction of highways, and the sprawl that would result, was an issue when the idea of an Interstate 90 connector was planned in East Greenbush. The preservation of historic landmarks is another issue RCG has been involved with including saving the Freihofer Building in Lansingburgh from being demolished and replaced by a drug store chain. Other initiatives undertaken by RCG are also documented in the organizations records.
Scope and Contents
The records of the Rensselaer County Greens (RCG) contain relevant information behind its efforts to protect the Rensselaer County community from the destruction of environment and historical landmarks. The records consist of applications, permits, court material, environmental statistics and research, news clippings, visual information, rulings, and audiovisuals. The main focus of the records is RCGs conflict with Besicorp and the factory the company planned to construct in Rensselaer.
The records were donated to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by member, Eric Daillie. Many of the papers are records he personally created or collected, including correspondence, speeches, and political information he composed. The records came in boxes that were for the most part organized. Much of the information was already in folders and binders. The original order of the records in the collection was largely maintained with a few exceptions.
The records lack comprehensive information about the membership of RCG other than Eric Daillie. The strength of the records lies in documenting how the organization viewed individuals and other organizations who held opposing views.
Several collections in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives provide further information on the environmental issues of concern to the Rensselaer County Greens. For a complete list of related collections see the subject guide for Conservation and the Environment. Of particular interest are the records of Tom Blandy (APAP-133), Jeanne Casatelli (APAP-150), and the Environmental Clearinghouse, Inc. (ECOS) (APAP-180).
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series: 1 - Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC: 1999-2004; 2 - BASF: 2000-2003, Undated; 3 - Chip Fab: 1998-2004, Undated; 4 - Series 4 - Other Projects: 2000-2004; Series 5 - Audiovisuals: 1999-2003.
Social Activists and Public Advocates; Rensselaer County, New York; Conservation and the Environment; Citizens' associations--New York (State)--Rensselear County; Environmental protection--New York (State)--Citizen participation; Historic preservation--New York (State); Permits; Briefs (legal documents); Clippings; Correspondence; Videocassettes; Audiocassettes; Rensselaer County (N.Y.) Greens; Besicorp
- Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:, 1999-2004; 1; 5.33 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  The multiple issues that Rensselaer County Greens (RCG) raised with this company can be seen in the diversity of the records in this series. Environmental issues were the primary priority with information pertaining to water pollution, air pollution, traffic congestion, previous contaminants in the ground where the new site was to be built, and the noise and smell that would be given off by the plant documented in the records. Application and permit material make up a major component of the series while background statistics and material directly from the court proceedings account for another large section of the series. The environmental concerns and research files were created to be used by RCG, and as a result the majority of the information in the series documents RCGs claims against Besicorp. The pros and cons of what Besicorp could mean for Rensselaer and what it could do to influence the lifestyles of Rensselaers citizens is documented in the various newspaper stories on the topic. RCG handouts give a clear statement of why the organization was fighting against the newly planned plant.
  - Application Material, Empire State Newsprint Project, Article X Preliminary Scoping Statement & SEQR Draft Scoping Document, 2000 January (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 1)
  - Application Material, State of New York Department of Public Service, 2000 December 12 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 2)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Table of Contents and Appendix, 2001 December (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 3)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Sections 1,2, 3, 2001 December (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 4)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Section 4, 2001 December (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 5)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Section 5, 2001 December (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 6)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Sections 6, 7, 2001 December (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 7)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Sections 8, 9, 2001 December (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 8)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Section 10, Appendix J, 2001 December (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 9)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Design and Visual Modifications relating to Section 10, 2001-2003 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 10)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Maps of Visual Resources (Relating to Section 10), 2001-2002 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 11)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Sections 11, 12, 2001 December (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 12)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Sections 13, 14, 2001 December (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 13)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Sections 15, 16, 2001 December (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 14)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Sections 17, 18, 2001 December (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 15)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Sections 19, 20, 2001 December (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 16)
  - Application Material, Article X, Empire State Newsprint Project, Section 21 and a memo on transportation, 2001 December (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 17)
  - Application Material, Draft Post-Remediation Construction Plan, Empire State Newsprint Projects and Article X Issues of Sierra Club Hudson Mohawk Group, 2002 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 18)
  - Application Material, New York State board on Electric Generation Siting and the Environment, 2002 October 23 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 19)
  - Application Material, Young, SommerLLC, aboutApplications for special permits, 2003 January (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 20)
  - Application Material, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, NYSDEC, and Department of Health, 2003 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 21)
  - Joint Settlement Material, Joint Settlement Agreement", 2003 June (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 22)
  - Joint Settlement Material, Table of Contents and Cover for Joint Application for Permit, 2003 April 25 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 23)
  - Joint Settlement Material, Exhibit 3 to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Joint Application for Permit", 2003 April 25 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 24)
  - Joint Settlement Material, Environmental Questionnaire", 2003 April 25 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 25)
  - Joint Settlement Material, Joint Proposal on State and Local Law Issues, (list of Exhibits in back), 2003 June 18 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 26)
  - Joint Settlement Material, BS&K, overview of material, 2003 June 18 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 27)
  - Joint Agreement Material, Federal Consistency Assessment Form, 2003 April 25 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 28)
  - Joint Agreement Material, Appendix A", 2003 April (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 29)
  - Joint Agreement Material, Appendix B-D", 2001; Undated (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 30)
  - Joint Agreement Material, Appendix E", 2003 April (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 31)
  - Joint Agreement Material, Appendix F", 2003 April (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 32)
  - Joint Agreement Material, Appendix G", 2002 October (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 33)
  - Joint Agreement Material, Related to Appendix G, Historic Architectural Evaluation, Appendix 1", 2001 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 34)
  - Joint Agreement Material, Related to Appendix G, Photos, Appendix 2", Undated (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 35)
  - Joint Agreement Material, Related to Appendix G, Correspondence, Appendix 3", 2001-2003 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 36)
  - Joint Agreement Material, Appendix H, 2002 May 24 (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 37)
  - Joint Agreement Material, Appendix I and Appendix J, 2003 April; Undated (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 38)
  - Joint Agreement Material, Appendix K-L, Undated (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 39)
  - Joint Agreement Material, Appendix M-N, Undated (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 40)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, 2 Volumes, Exhibit 4, NYSDEC Draft Permits and Fact Sheet Narratives, 2002 May (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 41)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Exhibit 4 continued, Air Pollution Control Permit, Undated (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 42)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Exhibit 4 continued, Permit, Undated (Box 1 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 43)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Exhibit 5, Letter, Virginia C. Robbins, Bond, Schoeneck & King, to Christopher Hogan, NYSDEC BEDCO comments on Draft PSD Permit", 2002 July 19 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 1)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Exhibit 6, BEDCO Responses to Sierra Club", 2002 August 16 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 2)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Exhibit 7, Air Quality Impact Assessment", 2003 April 28 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 3)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement,Exhibits 8-11, 2002 August 16; 2002 December 9; 2002 December 19; 2003 May 28 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 4)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Exhibit 12, BEDCO Responses to NYSDPS Staff Interrogatories", 2002 August 19 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 5)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement,Exhibits 13-15, 2003 April-June (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 6)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement,Exhibits 16-18, 2002 September 16; 2002 October 25; 2003 April (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 7)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Exhibit 19, Letter and Attachments, Kevin M. Bernstein to Judges Brilling and Garlick, Traffic Submission", 2002 September 19 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 8)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement,Exhibits 22, 23, 23a, 24, 2002 November 19; 2003 April 2; 2003 May 15; 2003 May 28 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 9)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement,Exhibits 25, 25a, 2002 November 12; 2002 December 16 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 10)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement,Exhibits 26-30, 2002 July 22; 2003 February 24; 2003 June; Undated (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 11)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Exhibit 31, Analysis of Alternatives Pursuant to Section 106for Demolition of Buildings 75, 87, and 88 at the BASF Facility, October 2002, 2002 October (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 12)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Exhibits 32-36, 2002 October 23; 2003 February 13; 2003 March 13; 2003 March 28; 2003 April 9 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 13)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Exhibit 37, BEDCO Responses to Interrogations", 2002 June 28 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 14)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Exhibit 37 continued, 2002 June 28 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 15)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Exhibit 38, RC/Greens Responses to BEDCO Interrogatories", 2002 September 19 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 16)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement, Exhibit 39, Revised Preliminary Landscape Plan", 2002 December 19 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 17)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement,Exhibits 40-43, 2002 November 8; 2002 December 2; 2003 April (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 18)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement,Exhibits 44-45, 2002 September 19; Undated (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 19)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement,Exhibits 46-47, 2003 February 6; 2003 June 2 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 20)
  - Exhibits to the Joint Settlement Agreement,Exhibits 100-106, 2002 August (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 21)
  - Visual Resources; BEDCO Response to RCG, 2003 September 22; Undated (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 22)
  - Evidentiary Hearing, Vol. 1, p. 1226-1400, 2003 September 17 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 23)
  - Evidentiary Hearing, Vol. 1, p. 1401-1587, 2003 September 17 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 24)
  - Evidentiary Hearing, Vol. 2, p. 1588-1800, 2003 September 19 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 25)
  - Evidentiary Hearing, Vol. 2, p. 1801-1980, 2003 September 19 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 26)
  - Evidentiary Hearing, Vol. 3, p. 2688-2800, 2003 September 26 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 27)
  - Evidentiary Hearing, Vol. 3, p. 2801-2898, 2003 September 26 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 28)
  - Affidavits, August 2003, 2003 August (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 29)
  - Interrogatories, Department of Public Service to Besicorp, 2002 August 8 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 30)
  - Interrogatories, Besicorp to Sierra Club, 2002 August (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 31)
  - Interrogatories, Besicorp to NYSDPS, 2002 August-November (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 32)
  - Interrogatories, Department of Public Service to Besicorp, 2004 March 1 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 33)
  - Testimonies, Packet of testimonies on the Empire State Newsprint Project, and an expert witness testimony list, 2002 June; 2003 August 12 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 34)
  - Testimonies, Testimonies on behalf of Besicorp (1 of 2), 2003 August 12 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 35)
  - Testimonies, Testimonies on behalf of Besicorp (2 of 2), 2003 August 12 (Box 2 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 36)
  - Testimonies, Testimony on Visual Impacts and Land Use/Waterfront Development by Besicorp, 2003 August 13 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 1)
  - Testimonies, Testimony Andrew Davis and Richard Powell, 2003 August 13 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 2)
  - Testimonies, Testimony on behalf of the Fort Crailo Neighborhood Association, 2003 August 14 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 3)
  - Testimonies, Testimony on behalf of the Fort Crailo Neighborhood Association, 2003 August 13; 2003 September 8 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 4)
  - Testimonies, Testimony of David Kahlbaugh on behalf of the City of Rensselaer, Undated (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 5)
  - Testimonies, Testimony of John Shafer on behalf of the City of Rensselaer, Undated (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 6)
  - Rebuttal Testimonies, list of Besicorp witnesses, and testimonies on behalf of Besicorp, 2003 August 27 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 7)
  - Rebuttal Testimonies, Testimonies on behalf of Besicorp, 2003 August 27 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 8)
  - Rebuttal Testimonies, Testimony of Stephen J. Savaria on behalf of Besicorp, 2003 August 27 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 9)
  - Rebuttal Testimonies, Testimony/Statement by Besicorp to the City of Rensselaer, 2003 August 27 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 10)
  - Rebuttal Testimonies, Testimony on behalf of the Department of Public Service, 2003 September 9 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 11)
  - Rebuttal Testimonies, Testimony by David Kahlbaugh on behalf of the City of Rensselaer, undated (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 12)
  - Exhibit list and RCG court paper without content, 2003-2004 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 13)
  - Correspondence of court information by email, 2002-2003 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 14)
  - Besicorp-Empire Project Mail List", Undated (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 15)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, BEDCO Comments, Undated (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 16)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, BEDCO Response, 2003 April 30 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 17)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, BEDCO Response to Comments, 2004 April 19 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 18)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, BEDCO Statement, 2003 August 12 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 19)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, BEDCO Briefs, 2003 April 19; 2004 July 14 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 20)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, BEDCO Initial Brief (1 of 2), Undated (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 21)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, BEDCO Initial Brief (2 of 2), Undated (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 22)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, BEDCO ReplyBriefs, Undated (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 23)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, BEDCO Public Information, 2002-2003 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 24)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, City of Rensselaer Briefs, 2003-2004 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 25)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, City of Rensselaer Motions, 2002 December 6; 2003 April 17 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 26)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, City of Rensselaer Statement, 2003 August 13 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 27)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, City of Rensselaer Reply, 2004 April 19 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 28)
  - Briefs, Decisions, Rulings, City of Rensselaer Petition for Full Party Status, 2002 July 3 (Box 3 (1-Besicorp-Empire Development Company, LLC:), Folder 29)